Malcolm Crum

Programmer and problem solver

021 234 8790 crummynz@gmail.com github.com/crummy malcolmcrum.com

I'm a software developer with four years experience delivering quality code and seven years working on first class software in fast-paced Scrum teams. In my next role I'm looking to work in a remote-flexible role for a customer-facing product in an environment that challenges me to continue to grow. I love to code and to mentor fellow colleagues, and I enjoy leading and learning in equal amounts.

Experience

DiUS Computing - Software Developer, 2019 to present

Worked on several projects uplifting older components and building new ones to integrate into existing systems for clients, including:

- Uplifting employee-management software written with Spring Boot to integrate with SAP
- Built out new Kotlin service supported with MySQL and RabbitMQ to ensure legal compliance for billing
- Work within client team to build new React UI and Kotlin backend to manage monthly interest distributions, using MongoDB and RabbitMQ, within existing microservice ecosystem
- Built out product backend for internal machine-learning project, working with AWS, NodeJS and React

TestObject / Sauce Labs - *Software Developer*, 2015 to 2018

Java and Angular development on our PaaS. Deeply involved in all aspects of the development process, from devops to deploys. Developed new features to reliably interact with physical Android and iOS devices, as well as maintaining and refactoring old code. Projects included:

- Integrated seamless HTTP proxy service for device testing, allowing customers to test apps and services that require private network communication
- Split monolith into independently deployable services for integration into multiple datacenters, **enabling global distribution** of real device cloud platform
- Migrated TestObject Angular UI to existing Sauce Labs React codebase

Sonos, Inc - Software Test Engineer, 2012 to 2015

Lead tester in a mature, fast-paced Scrum team. Took pride in ensuring first class quality over all of Sonos' software controllers.

Led feature and regression testing on seven major software releases for desktop and mobile platforms, including wireless setup, parallel updates, and an HTML5 webview for music services. Implemented strengthened testing practices and created tools to assist testing and development. Performed manual tests, created and set up automation frameworks and wrote automated tests for desktop and mobile apps.

Education

UC Santa Cruz - *Graduated 2012* Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Skills

- Capable and comfortable with Java, Kotlin, Docker
- Experience with NodeJS, AWS, Python, React, Kubernetes, Jenkins
- Scrum Master certified
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner